

email: ruaidriog@gmail.com website: eirewebdesian.com

mobile: 086 735 6166

Full Stack Web Developer/Designer

About me

I'm a 25 year old web developer from Ireland. I pride myself on my teamwork and eagerness to learn. I mix practicality, interactivity and art to create web applications.

Skills

As a full stack developer I have worked with both front and back end languages to design and develop professional level web applications.

HTML, CSS & Javascript

The foundation of every web application, I have spent the past 7 years working with these languages in every project I have developed. This includes frameworks such as Node.js, bootstrap, and using APIs such as Stripe

Any professional web application I have developed that requires back end coding has been written in PHP, giving me 4 years of experience with the language

MySQL

I have built all my databases using MySQL, including Well Red's

AJAX

Used in several web applications to communicate between back and front end

One year spent learning React for my final vear of college

Java

Building Android applications using Java in Android Studio

Wireframes

I have built wireframes using Azure for 3+ years

Clients

Well Red

Transformed a small business operating out of a local shop into an online school supply business that delivers to schools and teachers all across the country.

KIT-tc

Before leaving college, started development on this consulting companies website. Once completed I was brought on as an in house IT support and maintenance employee.

Various Freelance developments

Education

IADT 2015-2018

BSc in Computing (multimedia authoring and web engineering)

Graduated with second class honors

Trinity College Dublin 2013-2015

Computer Science

Coláiste Eoin 2007-2013

Leaving Certficiate (incl. H.Maths C1, Physics B2, Economics B2, French B2, Geography A2 Irish B1)

Experience

Freelance Web Development 2018-present

Experience working for a variety of clients, time management, project management, client relations, outsourcing and visual problem solving. During my time freelancing, I have had time to develop skills in design and development

KIT Training and Consulting 2018 IT support, web developer and maintenance

Musgrave Marketplace

2013-2017

General operative

Achievements

Friends From Ireland

Working as a volunteer to promote community development in Lesotho, Africa. This project was to build and extend a school for primary level children and also to run a pipe from a spring, high up in the mountains down to the village to provide access to clean water.

Diabetes Ireland

A member since 2007 of the Sweetpea Kids Club, the section of Diabetes Ireland focused on education, support and awareness of children with Type 1 Diabetes.

Player of the Year School Basketball Youngest starting Point Guard Trinity College

Various Gaelic Football & Hurling Awards